<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Suzan</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Suzan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Wrangling Part 4: Summarizing and slicing your data</title>
      <link>/2018/04/dplyr-tutorial-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/dplyr-tutorial-4/</guid>
      <description>This is the fourth blog post in a series of dplyr tutorials. In this tutorial we will summarizing our data: i) counting cases and observations, ii) creating summaries using summarise() and it&amp;rsquo;s summarise_all(), _if() and _at() variants, and iii) pulling the maximum and minimum row values.
Content:
   Counting cases and adding counts  Counting the number of observations Adding the number of observations in a column  Summarising data  Summarise all Summarise if Summarise at  Arranging rows Showing only part of your data  The 5 lowest and highest values A random selection of rows A user-defined slice of rows    Note: as per previous blog posts, I will present everything in the form of a pipe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on 4 months of GitHub: my advice to beginners</title>
      <link>/2018/03/reflections-4-months-of-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/reflections-4-months-of-github/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday marked my four months membership of GitHub. Back then, I had seen many GitHub repos pass by after joining Twitter a few weeks earlier, and I wanted to star some of them to find them back more easily. It took another 23 days before I actually committed something myself.
Now, four months later, I use GitHub (private) and GitLab (work) as good as daily, and I have inspired others to start using it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Wrangling Part 3: Basic and more advanced ways to filter rows</title>
      <link>/2018/02/dplyr-tutorial-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/dplyr-tutorial-3/</guid>
      <description>This is the third blog post in a series of dplyr tutorials:
 Part 1: Basic to Advanced Ways to Select Columns Part 2: Transforming your columns into the right shape  
Content:
 Basic row filters  Filtering rows based on a numeric variable Filtering based on a exact character variable matches Filtering rows based on regex Filtering based on multiple conditions Filtering out empty rows  Filtering across multiple columns  Filter_all Filter_if Filter_at    The data</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Galentine&#39;s Day!</title>
      <link>/2018/02/happy-galentines-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/happy-galentines-day/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes you dream big, but you just don&amp;rsquo;t have the data&amp;hellip;
I had this plan for text analysis by character from the Parks &amp;amp; Recreation series to celebrate Galentine&amp;rsquo;s Day but getting the data was a struggle. Subtitles are available for pretty much every episode but those don&amp;rsquo;t contain data about the character who said the lines. I needed scripts, which are a bit harder to come by. I found 6 scripts of episodes on the web from the first 3 seasons in pdf format that were usable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Wrangling Part 2: Transforming your columns into the right shape</title>
      <link>/2018/02/dplyr-tutorial-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/dplyr-tutorial-2/</guid>
      <description>This is a second post in a series of dplyr functions. The first one covered basic and advanced ways to select, rename and reorder columns,and can be found here: Data Wrangling Part 1
This second one covers tools to manipulate your columns to get them the way you want them.
 Mutating columns: the basics Mutating several columns at once  Mutate_all Mutate_if Mutate_at to change specific columns**](#mutate_at-to-change-specifc-columns)  Working with discrete columns  Recoding discrete columns Creating new discrete column (two levels) Creating new discrete column (multiple levels)  Splitting and merging columns Bringing in columns from other data tables Spreading and gathering data Turning data into NA</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Wrangling Part 1: Basic to Advanced Ways to Select Columns</title>
      <link>/2018/01/dplyr-tutorial-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/dplyr-tutorial-1/</guid>
      <description>I went through the entire dplyr documentation for a talk last week about pipes, which resulted in a few &amp;ldquo;aha!&amp;rdquo; moments. I discovered and re-discovered a few useful functions, which I wanted to collect in a few blog posts so I can share them with others.
This first post will cover ordering, naming and selecting columns. The next post will be about recoding and transforming columns, and after that I will move on to row selection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Postmortem Airtime Effect</title>
      <link>/2018/01/postmortemplaylist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/postmortemplaylist/</guid>
      <description>I was busy on a little side project on radio playlists when the news broke about the death of Dolores O’Riordan, front singer of The Cranberries. And sure enough, a few hours later I could see The Cranberries starting to pop up in the playlists.
Their second album No Need to Argue was one of my favourite CD&amp;rsquo;s as a teenager, and so I wondered: how many times would they be played?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who&#39;s on everyone&#39;s 2017 &#34;hit list&#34;?</title>
      <link>/2018/01/2017radiohitlist/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/01/2017radiohitlist/</guid>
      <description>At the end of the year, everyone is making lists. And radio stations are no exceptions.
Many of our radio stations have a weekly &amp;ldquo;people&amp;rsquo;s choice&amp;rdquo; music chart. Throughout the week, people submit their top 3 recent songs, and every week those votes turn into a music chart. At the end of the year, they collapse all those weekly charts into a larger one covering the entire year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bilingual Town Names</title>
      <link>/2017/12/bilingualtowns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/12/bilingualtowns/</guid>
      <description>It seems that we Belgians just love confusing foreigners…
Imagine wanting to take a train to Mons from Ghent but there only is one driving to Bergen. Or driving south with a GPS telling you to follow the direcion of Liège, but for a while you will only see signs to Luik.
Mons/Bergen, Liège/Luik, Ypres/Ieper… those names refer to exactly the same city - one of them is the official French name, the other one the official Dutch one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Any Joke&#39;s left in Belgium?</title>
      <link>/2017/12/any-joke-s-left-in-belgium/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/12/any-joke-s-left-in-belgium/</guid>
      <description>What I was wondering: are there still Joke&amp;rsquo;s born in Belgium? Every time I pass by a colleague named Joke, I wonder. Let me explain: Joke is quite regular Dutch first name for a girl. You pronounce it [yo-ke], like blending &amp;lsquo;yoghurt&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;kebab&amp;rsquo; together and put the accent on the &amp;lsquo;yo&amp;rsquo;. &amp;lsquo;Joke&amp;rsquo; is just a diminutive form of Jo, kind of like Jenny, Abby and Debby. No-one who grew up speaking Dutch would bat an eye to hear about someone named Joke, but everyone else on this planet probably would.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>